<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE legalnotice [
<!ENTITY % vars SYSTEM "../common/vars.xml">
%vars;]>
<legalnotice xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  version="5.0"
  xml:id="tmdisclaim">
<title>Legal Notices</title>
  <para>Progress Software Corporation and/or its subsidiaries may have patents, patent
applications, trademarks, copyrights, or other intellectual property rights covering
subject matter in this publication. Except as expressly provided in any written license
agreement from Progress Software Corporation, the furnishing of this publication does
not give you any license to these patents, trademarks, copyrights, or other intellectual
property. Any rights not expressly granted herein are reserved.</para>
  <para>Progress, IONA, IONA Technologies, the IONA logo, Orbix, High Performance 
Integration, Artix;, FUSE, and Making Software Work Together are trademarks or 
registered trademarks of Progress Software Corporation and/or its subsidiaries in the 
US and other countries.</para>
  <para>Java and J2EE are trademarks or registered trademarks of Sun 
Microsystems, Inc. in the United States and other countries. CORBA is a 
trademark or registered trademark of the Object Management Group, Inc. in the 
US and other countries. All other trademarks that appear herein are 
the property of their respective owners.</para>
    <para>While the information in this publication is believed to be accurate Progress Software Corporation makes no
warranty of any kind to this material including, but not limited to, the implied warranties of merchantability and
fitness for a particular purpose. Progress Software Corporation shall not be liable for errors contained herein, or
for incidental or consequential damages in connection with the furnishing, performance or use of this material.</para>
    <para>All products or services mentioned in this manual are covered by the trademarks, service marks, or product
      names as designated by the companies who market those products.</para>
  <para>No part of this publication may be reproduced, stored in a retrieval system or transmitted, in any form or by any means, photocopying, 
    recording or otherwise, without prior written consent of Progress Software Corporation. No third-party intellectual property right liability is 
    assumed with respect to the use of the information contained herein. Progress Software Corporation assumes no responsibility for errors or 
    omissions contained in this publication. This publication and features described herein are subject to change without notice. Portions of this 
    document may include Apache Foundation documentation, all rights reserved.</para>
</legalnotice>